A world where heroes come in all sizes and
adventure is the greatest magic of all.
Willow is a fantasy, adventure, action film directed by Ron Howard.
The evil Queen Bavmorda hunts the newborn princess Elora Danan,
a child prophesied to bring about her downfall.
When the royal infant is found by Willow, a timid farmer and aspiring
sorcerer, he's entrusted with delivering her from evil.
Madmartigan, played by Val Kilmer.
Sorsha, played by Joanne Whalley.
Willow, played by Warwick Davis.
Raziel, played by Patricia Hayes.
Airk, played by Gavan O'Herlihy.
Vohnkar, played by Phil Fondacaro.
Willow is a 1988 American high fantasy adventure film
directed by Ron Howard and produced by Nigel Wooll.
The film was executive produced by George Lucas and
written by Bob Dolman from a story by Lucas.
The film stars Warwick Davis as the title character, Val
Kilmer, Joanne Whalley, Billy Barty and Jean Marsh.
Davis portrays aspiring magician Willow Ufgood who teams up with disaffected warrior Madmartigan
(Kilmer) to protect young baby princess Elora Danan from evil queen Bavmorda (Marsh).
Lucas conceived the idea for the film in 1972, approaching Howard to
direct during the post-production phase of Cocoon in 1985.
Bob Dolman was brought in to write the screenplay, coming up with seven
drafts that Lucas was actively involved in developing.
It was finished in late 1986.
It was then set up at Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM) and principal
photography began in April 1987, finishing the following October.
The majority of filming took place in Dinorwic quarry in Wales with some at Elstree
Studios in Hertfordshire, as well as a small section in New Zealand.
Industrial Light & Magic created the visual effects and animation sequences, which
led to a revolutionary breakthrough with digital morphing technology.
The film was released in 1988 to mixed reviews from critics with praise for the visual effects, humour, character
designs and Warwick Davis's performances but criticism for its direction, pacing, tone and story.
It grossed $137.6 million worldwide against a $35 million budget.
While not the blockbuster some expected, it turned a profit based on international
box office returns and strong home video and television returns.
It received two Academy Award nominations.
A television series that served as a sequel to the
film was released on Disney+ in 2022.
The film explores themes of mission, hero, baby, monster, magic.